#### Contact

narenbaburs@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/naren-babu (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

Machine Learning
Deep Learning
Python

### Languages

English, Tamil, Hindi

### Certifications

Convolutional Neural Networks
Data Scientist with Python Track
Data Analyst with Python Track
Machine Learning
Git for Data Science

# Naren Babu

R&D Engineer AI/ML

Chennai

## Summary

I have done my Masters in Computational Engineering with specialization in Artificial Intelligence and Data Science and having nearly 2 years of experience in Product Development using Al algorithm. I have Solid Experience in building various Al products from scratch and I'm extremely hands-on and have experience in building and maintaining data pipelines.

# Experience

IN-D - Power of AI
R&D Engineer AI/ML
July 2020 - Present (2 months)
Greater Chennai Area

Tango IT

Data Scientist

August 2018 - April 2020 (1 year 9 months)

Greater Chennai Area, India

Project Title: Person Re-identification

Description: The project aimed at identifying the unique persons across all

cameras, with

the existing setup in the store. Trained a model with 3.5 lac images of 10,000

identities,

semi-automated the manual correction process thus cutting cost from 9 people

to 3 people

Project Title: Face Recognition

Description: Helped the Greater Chennai Police in finding offenders during

Diwali 2019.

Trained the model with 63212 offenders with each offender having 1 image for

training. Also

improved the search speed for recognizing the faces by 10x times.

Project Title: Data Collection

Page 1 of 2

Description: Successfully implemented a data collection module at stores in a cost-effective

manner. Initially each camera required an edge device (1 Camera = 1 Device in a store,

being 1:1 Camera to Device ratio), however post successful modifications, this resulted in

bringing down to one device per store (1 Device = 1 Store, 1:1 Device to Store ratio)

Project Title: Smart Parking

Description: Implemented a smart parking pilot for leading product company to find the availability of parking lots, detect violated parking and authorize cars approaching with upto 30 kmph speed in the parking area for nearly 400 cars

Fibercat Technology
Trainee
May 2017 - August 2017 (4 months)
Greater Chennai Area

Restructured, reworked and resolved SQL queries during the implementation of GST in 2017 for Johnson Lifts

## Education

Amrita Vishwa Vidyapeetham, Coimbatore

Master of Technology - MTech, Computational Engineering · (2017 - 2019)

Panimalar Engineering College
Bachelor of Engineering - BE, Computer Science · (2013 - 2017)